{
    "questions": 
    [
        {   "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "The area of Europe where the Vikings came from is called?",
            "a": "Mesopotamia",
            "b": "Valhalla",
            "c": "The Tundra",
            "d": "Scandinavia",
            "correct": "Scandinavia"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings", 
            "question": "What were Vikings also called?",
            "a": "Norsemen",
            "b": "Sheep",
            "c": "Pilgrims",
            "d": "Monks",
            "correct": "Norsemen"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "Vikings could be described as?",
            "a": "Astronauts",
            "b": "Deep sea fishermen",
            "c": "Bean farmers",
            "d": "Raiders",
            "correct": "Raiders"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What abilities are Vikings best known for?",
            "a": "Writing",
            "b": "Ship Building and Sailing",
            "c": "Reading",
            "d": "Mathematics",
            "correct": "Ship Building and Sailing"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What would craftworkers carve into wood to be placed on ships?",
            "a": "Dragon Heads",
            "b": "Tools",
            "c": "Armor",
            "d": "Banners",
            "correct": "Dragon Heads"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What would vikings call it when they went raiding?",
            "a": "Pleasant",
            "b": "Good times",
            "c": "To go a stealing",
            "d": "To go a viking",
            "correct": "To go a viking"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What were the fiercest Viking warriors called?",
            "a": "Ragers",
            "b": "Celts",
            "c": "Navy Seals",
            "d": "Beserkers",
            "correct": "Beserkers"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "Why was farmland scarse in the Viking homelands?",
            "a": "Too many people",
            "b": "Wolves owned the countryside",
            "c": "Many mountains",
            "d": "High winds",
            "correct": "Many mountains"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "Where were Viking farms located?",
            "a": "Underground using candles as light sources",
            "b": "On floating platforms in the ocean",
            "c": "In dedicated rooms of their homes",
            "d": "In between fjords and mountains",
            "correct": "In between fjords and mountains"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What were the Viking alphabet letters called?",
            "a": "Stick figures",
            "b": "Runes",
            "c": "Symbols",
            "d": "Ode to Thunder",
            "correct": "Runes"
        },
        
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "How did many Europeans feel about Vikings?",
            "a": "They wanted to adopt the Viking culture",
            "b": "They feared Vikings",
            "c": "They loved Vikings",
            "d": "They welcomed Vikings into their homes",
            "correct": "They feared Vikings"
        },

{
    "a": "Digital maps",
     "c": "GPS", 
     "b": "A compass",
     "d": "The sun and the stars", 
     "question": "The Vikings navigated by using what?", 
      "topic": "Vikings",
      "correct":"The sun and the stars"},

{"a": "Sweden",
 "c": "Greenland",
"b": "Constantinople", 
"d": "Mexico",
"question": "After being banished from Iceland, Eric the Red went to?",
 "topic": "Vikings",
 "correct": "Greenland"},

{"a": "To teach to talk", 
"c": "To hunt rats",
"b": "To help them if they got lost",
"d": "As loyal companions",
"question": "Why did Vikings take birds to sea?", 
"topic": "Vikings",
"correct":"To help them if they got lost" },

{"a": "Philosopher",
 "c": "Emperor",
 "b": "Scientist", 
 "d": "Explorer",
  "question": "Leif Ericson is famous for being a?", 
  "topic": "Vikings",
  "correct":"Explorer"},

{"a": "To attract settlers",
 "c": "It matched the environment found in Greenland",
 "b": "It was selected randomly",
 "d": "Eric the Red's daughter liked the name", 
 "question": "Why was Greenland given its name?", 
 "topic": "Vikings",
 "correct": "To attract settlers"},

{"a": "From the Big Bang", 
"c": "By the trees",
 "b": "By the goddess of love", 
 "d": "From ice, mist and snow", 
 "question": "How was the world created according to Norse Mythology?",
 "topic": "Vikings",
 "correct": "From ice, mist and snow"},

{"a": "Play tiddly winks",
 "c": "Listen to harp music",
 "b": "Sit in hot tubs", 
 "d": "Battle by day and feast at night", 
 "question": "What do Odin and the warriors do in Valhalla?",
  "topic": "Vikings",
  "correct":  "Battle by day and feast at night" },

{"a": "Thursday", 
"c": "Friday",
"b": "Monday",
"d": "Tuesday", 
"question": "What weekday is named after Thor, the Viking god of Thunder?", 
"topic": "Vikings",
"correct":"Thursday"}

    ]
}